請讓一讓
Make way please.
你從樓梯上
You from the staircase.
有人了，走
Somebody is there. Go.
那邊
Over there.
追
Chase.
慘，前面沒路可去，退後吧
Dead end, shucks! Back out.
在那邊
That way.
怎麼樣？
How's that?
博一博
Try my luck.
坐穩
Sit tight.
分頭找
Let's split up.
力奇，那邊
Ricky, over there.
放心，他們倆一定找不到我們的
They won't find us.
還想逃
Hold it.
麻煩你替我拍張照片
Please take a photo for me.
謝謝
Thanks.
多拍一張
Please take one more.
來，我跟你怕
l do for you.
好了吧？    謝謝
lt's done? Thanks.
力奇
Ricky.
你厲害
You're great.
那些相已經曬出來
The photos have been developed.
所以說你進了我們的俱樂部會有好處
lt's good for you to join our club.
只要那警察進入我們的範圍就死定
That cop will die once entering our territory.
阿萍，快聽電話
Ping, answer the phone.
二十四小時都這麼多電話
Do l have to answer them all day?
我是負責接收全世界臥底的電話的
l'm collecting information worldwide.
HELLO…
HELLO, HELLO
Vl…
Vl, Vl
你試試保加利亞的那一個
Try the one in Bulgaria.
MAH…A
MAHA, MAHA.
喂…
Hello...
你自己聽吧
Take this one yourself.
OL…A
OLA, OLA.
MADALl…
MADALl, MADALl.
是日本來的
lt's from Japan.
MUSHl…
MUSHl, MUSHl.
曹警司，我是鐵力威
Superintendent, l'm Muscles.
我找到他了
l've found him.
那混蛋終於出現了
He finally appears.
那你還不快把他抓回來
Get him back right away.
我們拿他沒辦法
We can't do anything.
連力奇也給他們抓住了
They've even caught Ricky.
很容易，我派人來幫你忙就行了
Easy, l'll send someone to help you.
沒用的
lt doesn't help.
他已經查清楚我們香港特警組的底
They know everything about our group.
那怎麼辦？
What should we do?
幫我找孤兒院的死黨鷓鴣菜來幫我忙
Go find my buddy Kidstuff in the orphanage.
什麼，鷓鴣菜
What? Kidsstuff.
大哥，七號倉的貨再不出很易出事的
We must unload, before they go wrong.
現在的貨跟外面的價錢怎樣比較？
What's the profit ratio?
大概三十二倍左右
About 32 times.
賣了它吧，我還以為可以一本萬利
Sold; thought l could make a good deal.
大哥，的奇又跟小林打架了
They are fighting again.
他又為什麼打架？
Over what?
是為阿霞
Over that girl Lin Ching-hsia.
把阿霞交給我
Give me that Lin Ching-hsia.
這張照片叫他們每人貼一個禮拜
They paste her on alternate weeks.
那就行了
That will do.
大哥，張曼玉
That's Miss Chang.
乾不乾淨？
ls she clean?
當然是乾淨，只不過包過雞翼
Of course, only used once as wrapper.
收起來，留給我
Save her for me.
快點做事
Get on with work.
SlR
SlR.
叫三號倉那些囚犯全都過來
Get all prisoners in No.3 here.
是
Yes, sir.
七一八一    有
7181 Yes.
五七三四    有
5734 Yes.
六三七七    有
6377 Yes.
過來
Come here!
SlR…
SlR.
SIR，他們都來了
They are all here.
沒事了，叫一六六三過來
Okay now. Get 1663 over.
是
Yes, sir.
你們回去做工
Go back to work.
是
Yes, sir.
一六六三    有
1663 Yes.
過來
Come here.
SlR
SlR.
一六六三，你今天可以出獄了
1663, you may be freed today.
SIR，你是說我今天可以出獄了嗎？
Sir, you're letting me out today?
SIR，你別跟我開玩笑了
You must be joking, l know.
我計算得很清楚的
l've calculated correctly.
連公眾假期和星期日算在一起
l can count too. Less the holidays and Sundays.
起碼也要做到中秋
l'll be here until Moon Festival.
因為你在獄中行為良好
You're paroled on good conduct.
所以提前釋放，你走吧
Go.
真的嗎？
ls it for real?
我跟你開慣笑的嗎？
Have l ever cheated you?
SIR，那麼我要去取回包頭了
Sir, let me do some packing.
就是那些手錶、戒指和打火機
There are a few loose ends.
不用了，這兒有五百元
No need;
就當是警方賠償你的損失
here's $500 as your compensation.
你馬上離開這裏
You leave here immediately.
我跟那些兄弟說幾句話可以嗎？
Let me say goodbye to them.
給你三十秒鐘
30 seconds.
謝謝你，阿SIR
Thanks, Sir.
現在我出獄了
l'm leaving 4 packs of Marlboro
我有四包萬寶路放在花盆底下
under the pos.
床底下的可樂差不多有大半罐
A coke under the bed.
分給兄弟們喝了吧
Let the brothers drink it.
別忘了替我把鍾楚紅
Take care of my movie stars.
李賽鳳、甄妮，胡茵夢收起來
Don't forget to hide the stars.
一六六三，時間到了
1663. Time's up.
是
Yes, sir.
阿SIR，我走了
Sir, l am leaving.
拜拜阿SIR，再見阿SIR
Good bye, Sir.
我要飛上天上
l'm going up, up and away.
別動…
Don't move.
我犯了什麼罪了？
l didn't do anything wrong.
越獄
Attempted jail breaking.
分明是誣害我
lt's clearly a frame-up.
你知道就好了
As long as you know it.
如果你跟警方合作，逃獄改為放監
You cooperate; you're free on parole.
別外還有二百萬元獎金
Plus a bonus of 2 million.
第三次世界大戰是嗎？
lt may be another World War.
沒那麼嚴重
Not so serious.
只是希望你和警方合作
You're to get somebody...
引渡一個人回來歸案
extradited back.
是警察？
ls he a cop too?
樹大有枯枝
People are people.
我們警務人員之中有個敗類
There's a rotten apple in the Force.
挾帶特警組
He absconded to Japan.
緝獲的那批價值一億美元的珠寶
Taking $100 million
逃往日本
in contraband diamond.
投靠一個名為稻草人俱樂部的組織
He's now protected by a Scarecrow Club.
這件事警方不便追查
We can't really do it ourselves.
想借助閣下的犯罪天才
We think highly your criminal genius.
實行以毒攻毒
Let's use evil means to handle the evil.
說得好聽點好不好
Can't you say it in a nice way?
我是因為超重考不到警察才做賊的
l stole because l flunked the cops test.
所以我早說過要更改投考警員的限制
You've got to liberalize employment rules.
現在一句話
Let's get this over.
你做還是不做？
Do you or don't you do it?
做，但是我一定要找我的死黨幫忙
Okay but l need my pals.
我不管你找什麼朋友來幫忙
lt's none of my business.
在二十四小時之內
Report to this address.
你要到這個地址報到，等候我的命令
After twenty-four hours.
先付點定金行不行？
Some down payment, okay?
我早就預你有這一招的
l knew you'd say that.
你把你的死黨名字先寫給我
Give me your friend's names.
走吧，沒錢別想買了
Looking around; yet with no money.
剛才的那齣戲很好看是嗎？    是
That was quite some show, eh? Yes
花旗參
Hey, Herb.
一共有五隻蛀牙，上面三隻下面兩隻
Five decayed teeth.
三千塊錢
$3000
什麼？再講一次
Say it once again.
五千
Five thousand.
聽不清楚
l still didn't get.
七千
Seven thousand.
我哪有這麼多蛀牙，再多開一個價錢
Name another price.
一萬，我只有這些錢了
$10,000. Only have that much.
算了，拿來
lt's a deal. Fork over.
醒目一點，不然刀拔出來會變成紅色
Be careful or you might get hacked.
進來
Come in!
醫生，陳百萬在外面
A Millionaire Chan...
他說沒空想先看
wants to be treated now.
叫他在外邊等兩分鐘
Tell him to wait two minutes.
來了個陳百萬，這就不能放過了
A millionaire! Won't let him slip away.
他是…
He is...
我知，他叫陳百萬
Millionaire Chan.
夠膽這個名字沒百萬也有十萬
lf now a million, at least some money.
別亂來
Stop talking nonsense.
什麼亂來，少廢話，走過那邊
Hold. Say nothing. Go this way, fast.
你別這樣
Don't be like that.
別這樣？你跟牙醫出去鬼混的時候
No more? Did you ever say 'no more'
有沒有想到不好
when with the dentist.
沒有
No.
陳先生，別生氣
Don't get angry.
陳先生，請進來
Come in, please.
我…
l...
閣下是陳百萬先生是嗎？
Aren't you Millionaire Chan?
是，你認識我嗎？
Yes, so you know me.
醫者父母心
A kind-heartiest dentist doesn't.
所有蛀牙、爛牙、補牙、鑲牙的人
Everyone who needs dental care
都像兒女一樣，無所謂識與不識
Have to know his patient.
你認不認識她？
Do you know her?
舊相識
lt's long gone.
舊相識？
Long gone?
這麼說你跟她有不可告人的事了
You had this with her then.
不可告人？是不是有關係？
Had this? Did you mean relationship?
當然是有
l did have.
那你知不知道我跟她有關係？
Don't you know my relationship with her?
什麼關係？
What then?
是夫婦
That of a husband and wife.
怎麼這麼巧
What a coincidence!
這次你死而無怨了吧
Now you know why you must die.
兄弟，你看清楚我不是他
l'm not him.
你膽敢說他不是姦夫？
You dare say he is not your lover?
是，是他
That's him all right.
事到如今
Time has come for you
你該把男子漢大丈夫的本色拿出來
to act like a real man.
本色我是有，但我不認識你
l'm a man but l don't know you.
我要打死你這對姦夫淫婦
l'm going to kill you lover.
你別這樣，別這樣
Stop it.
別這樣    走開
Don't do that. Get lost.
別動，我們是警察
Freeze, ClD.
你是誰？
Who are you?
我是賊
l am a thief.
那就是警察捉賊，順利成章
Good, a perfect copper-robber game.
三六二二
是
Here.
帶他回去
Take him back.
做賊，走
A thief? Get going.
你們不許動，軍裝警察馬上就來了
Don't move. Cops are coming.
我是哥倫布，美洲是我發現的
l'm Christopher Columbus. l discovered Amer.
你怎麼帶這麼瘦的狗逛街
Walking your skinny dog?
這只是狗嗎？這是鴨子
He's no dog. He's a duck.
我是問這只鴨，關你什麼事，再見
l was asking the duck, not you. See you.
集中精神，意志專一
Concentrate.
我要你生蛋，生蛋…
l want to lay eggs, lay eggs.
他是個神經漢，還找他幹什麼？
Why are you looking for that psychotic?
他比你清醒得多
He's much saner than you.
有哪裏比這裏更好，有得吃有得住
There's no place like this place.
不用花錢又不用傷腦筋
Everything free; even worry free.
他在那邊
Hey, he's over there.
大生地
Sandy.
原來是你們，有什麼好世界撈
Anything profitable for me.
當然有，不然找你幹什麼？
That's why l'm looking you up.
好的…又有好日子過了
Good, good days are here again.
走了…
Gone...
發達了，這次輪到我發了
This time l'll be rich.
這隻狗送給你
Get this dog of your back.
這只是母狗
But it's a bitch.
今晚打麻將
How about a few rounds tonight?
A few rounds tonight.
今晚打麻將
l mean playing mahjong.
A few rounds tonight!
幾點鐘？
When to start?
幾點鐘呢？
幾點鐘？
When to start?
我是說幾點鐘？
三點鐘
3 o'clock.
你約人了
Get the other player.
你為什麼不去做事？
Why didn't you go to work?
你為什麼走來走去不做事？
你為什麼走來去去不做事？
Why didn't you go to work?
這裏很噪，我聽不見
Too noisy. Can't hear you.
幹什麼？
What are you doing exactly?
誰叫他罵我，我就要跟他作對
l'll take on anyone who helps him scold me.
我喜歡搬來搬去都是這箱
l deliberately moved the Coke around.
吃飯了
Time to eat.
從前你不是帶著羅漢果做事的嗎？
You were with Roundhead.
為什麼會到這裏來做事
How come he's working here.
從前他姐姐沒結婚當然帶著他
l took him when his sister was unmarried.
現在嫁了還帶著他幹什麼
Now she's. No need to tug him along.
老朋友，羅漢果在哪裏？
Friend, know where Roundhead is?
到外面吃東西去了
Out for some food.
派快點，趕著要開工的
Hurry up, we have to work.
贏了
Won.
又是他贏
He won again.
那只蒼蠅本來是飛來我這邊的
That fly's supposed to fly towards me.
在那邊
That way.
終於讓我贏一次
So l finally win once.
這次本來是我贏的…
l'm supposed to win.
大哥，大哥大，大大哥，大哥大大
Big brother, brother big, big big brother.
不要再托汽水了，跟我們走吧
Don't transport soft drinks anymore, follow us.
我不玩，你們慢慢玩，我要去發財了
You have a good time. l'm going to get rich.
那我們怎麼辦…
What should we do...
剛剛你們玩的是什麼牌
What are you playing?
非洲十三張
African poker.
非洲十三張？怎麼玩的？
African poker? How do you play it?
很簡單，跟十三張一樣玩法
lt's easy. lt's similar to the Cantonese way.
每人派十三張牌拿著
Each person takes thirteen cards.
看那蒼蠅飛在誰的牌上，誰就贏
The person who gets the fly rested on his cards wins.
鷓鴣菜，我不知道你叫我們做什麼
Kidstuff, l don't know what you're asking us to do.
總之無論是什麼行動也好
No matter what kind of mission it is.
有羅漢果就沒有我
l will notjoin if Roundhead's in.
我不喜歡跟智商那麼低的人做事
l hate to work with the mentally retarded.
他也是我們的兄弟
He's our brother too.
雖然他智商比較低，但他很有義氣
He's dumb, but he's loyal.
義氣？兒戲才是
Loyal? l don't think so.
你試叫他仆街看他願不願意？義氣
He'll run away if you ask him to fall down on the street.
羅漢果，我叫你出來是要叫你做件事
Roundhead, l want you to do something.
或許會有危險…
lt may be dangerous.
不用說了大哥，你叫我做什麼也行
Alright, l'll do whatever you ask me to do.
但要我做策劃就免談
But l don't want to be the leader.
就算叫我賣命也沒問題
l'll even die for you.
那如果叫你仆街呢？
What if l ask you to fall down on the street.
報告大哥，我仆街了
Big brother, l'm falling down on the street.
在開車的時候別看書
Hey, you can't read while driving.
轉左…
Turn left...
撞車
A crackup.
真夠運
A close save.
想撞死人嗎？
What's come to you?
對不起，我搭錯車了
Sorry, got into the wrong car.
大生地，你怎麼開車的？
Sandy, you really can drive?
先對外後對內
Deal with the outsiders first.
鷓鴣菜，你去辦妥貨車司機
Kidstuff, try to convince the trucker.
我去辦妥小巴司機
l'll take care of the cabbie.
老朋友
Hello! Friend.
我們怎麼辦？
What to do now?
不用怕，我們要扭橫折曲
Don't be afraid. We're going to bluff.
先聲奪人，大聲兼惡，明白嗎？
Making a lot of strong noise. See?
知道嗎？
Do you know about it?
知道    走
Surely. Go.
今日天朗氣清，清風和暢
Weather is sublime today.
行人摩肩接踵，馬路上車水馬龍
Look at the hurrying steps and snaking traffic.
車來車往，南北西東
Cars come and go in all directions.
左上右落，有前有後，你進我退
There is discipline in organized confusion.
你這臭小子，撞壞我的車子？
You hit my car!
說話要想清楚才好說
Be careful with your words.
對了，花旗參
Say, Herb,
上個月不是讓人家撞壞了車
your care was damaged, eh?
那小子後來怎麼樣了？
What happened to him?
已經變了我家裏的地毯了
He's now my doormat.
它一邊有毛一邊沒有毛
Smooth this side; shaggy the other.
我的朋友看見了
My friend saw it.
還以為我打中了一隻癩皮熊呢
Someone mistakes him for a grizzly.
西牛皮，上次弄花了你車子那個人
Rawhide, how is the one
現在怎麼樣了？
who scraped you can.
算了吧，吞進肚子的東西別再提了
Don't usually talk about digested food.
鷓鴣菜，你呢？
Kidstuff, about about you?
我？我比較仁慈一點
Poor kindhearted me?
我把它放進玻璃瓶裏，用藥水浸著
l pickled him in ajar.
送給香港大學做標本了
And donated it to the University.
羅漢果，把你的本領告訴這位兄弟
Roundhead, tell him about you.
我？我被撞了車之後
Me? lf someone damaged my car.
馬上就下車然後說對不起
Get down and apologize.
跟著把皮包拿出來
Then take out the bag.
把所有的錢都給他
Give him all the money in the wallet.
然後說我下次不敢了，請原諒我吧
And promise not to do it again.
你這小子
Useless kid.
各位大哥
But that's exactly...
因為當時的情形跟現在一模一樣
what happened.
絕對不能亂車大炮的
l didn't try to fool you.
小舅子，有什麼事告訴我好了
Tell me.
是不是他們欺負你
Aren't they leaning on you?
是
Right.
原來是自己人
One big family.
其實我一聽你們說話的口音
Your accent.
就知道大家是海陸豐
Tells me we come from the same place.
想不到就快展開一場大廝殺了
One mistake, and there's a massacre.
一句說話就可以化干戈為玉帛
A right word and there's peace.
對不起…
Sorry...
別客氣，自己人太客氣反而見外
You don't have to be too kind to own people.
好了，和平了…
Okay now, we have peace.
開走所有車子，別阻礙大眾市民
Let's drive it away to unblock traffic.
就這樣吧
Let's do it.
兄弟，你說潮洲人是不是很團結的？
Say, shouldn't we be united?
對
Definitely.
潮州人是否向來是打死不離親兄弟？
Shouldn't we go shoulder to shoulder?
對
Surely so.
潮州人是不是一向對外不對內的？
Shouldn't we defy only outsiders?
對
Correct.
那麼你說，生為一個潮州人的我
Tell me, since l'm one of us.
面對著自己人的潮州人
And face to face with angry own folks.
我用不用怕？
Should l be scared?
當然不用怕
You have no reason to be scared.
不過你擋著我的去路，我有點怕
But l am scared being blocked by you.
你讓我們先出去，行不行？
Let us go out first, okay?
你可以他們不可以
Okay for you. Not for them.
沒理由，他們都是潮州人
But we are own folks.
不過來了香港很久，學會了多種語言
Although they've picked up local accent.
他們的樣子不像
They are different from you.
樣子會變的
Just in appearance.
是的…
Yes...
阿朗哥，用潮洲話念這首床前明月光
Read out a poem in.
給這位大叔聽聽
Our accent for his benefit.
對，你念
Read it.
隨便，隨便講點潮州話
Or a few words in our dialect.
SEVENELEVEN
SEVEN ELEVEN
什麼？
What?
SEVENELEVEN了
l say seven eleven.
兄弟，他講的不是潮州話
He isn't speaking Chiuchow.
是嗎？
ls that right?
平時就叫你多講點潮州話你就不聽
You wouldn't listen to my advice.
你說，現在怎麼辦？
Now what should we do?
別多講了，難道你們潮州人最兇？
No more idle talk. What do you want?
搞什麼心靈感應，弄到我們進退兩難
ESP really? You got us in a dilemma.
我歡喜，車子是偷來的，撞了就算
l rammed my own car.
你們自己懦弱，不敢面對強敵
So you cowards won't face the enemy.
對，這次最沒用的就是鷓鴣菜了
And the biggest coward is Kidstuff.
老是說一個能打百多個
Despite his boasts,
現在幾十個都嚇呆了
he's now mortified.
什麼？你還說我
What's this to do with me?
要不是你那句SEVENELEVEN
Your Seven Eleven.
用不著弄成這個樣子
lt got us into real trouble.
算了…別吵，隨便找個人來背鍋好了
Let bygones be bygones.
好
Surely.
好是嗎？
Surely what?
都是你臭小子
Surely your seven eleven.
只是會SEVENELEVEN
You don't know anything.
是識SEVENELEVEN了
Seven eleven.
是SEVENELEVEN
lt is SEVEN ELEVEN
好了…別吵了
All right, no more squabble.
麻煩你，去這個地方
Excuse me, this place at one time.
是什麼地方
What's this place.
就是那兒
l meant this place.
就是什麼地方？
Then what's this place?
我也不知道
Don't know!
照地址去，到了那裏就知道了
Would know when there.
鷓鴣菜，這是什麼地方？
Kidstuff, what's this place.
我也不知道
Don't know.
是我的當事人叫我來這裏接洽的
He told me to come here.
花旗參
Herb,
依我看這房子比你和我還要老
the house's older than you and me.
肯定是比我還要老，但未必比你老
Older than me, for sure.
老不老不成問題，最要緊的不是危樓
Okay, but is it a condemned house?
是危樓也沒問題
Even a condemned house is okay.
只有兩層高，摔下來也不會死
2 stories; won't kill anybody.
最怕是著火，一著火就慘了
But a fire would be disastrous.
不過大家小心點，就沒事的了
lt's okay if we are careful.
最怕是有鬼，有鬼也不稀奇
There may be ghosts, truly.
怎麼能知道以前的人怎樣死的？
People could very well have died there.
你說完了沒有？
Are you finished?
講完了
Finished.
走吧
Let's go.
壞的不靈好的靈，壞不靈好的靈…
Something's got to give, good or bad.
這裏跟外邊完全不同
Hey, it's so different from outside.
簡直是有場內場外的感覺
The mood's so different.
何止是場內場外，連色調也很配合我
Wonderful. Even the colors match.
對，我也覺得這裏很像雞竇跟你很配
Looks like a brothel. Suits you.
怎樣？
What now?
幫我一個忙行不行
You must help out.
什麼事？
What then?
等會我眼睛集中在看一樣東西的話
When you see us concentrate on a thing.
就分散我的注意力
Try to divert our attention.
沒問題
No problem.
坐
Sit down please.
正點
Great.
鷓鴣菜，我們的人都到齊了
Kidstuff, we are all here.
有什麼事不妨坦誠的說
Say it.
何心要我們猜呢
Leave nothing to imagination.
我這一輩子最討厭是用腦的
l hate brain exercises.
不是討厭，是沒腦子
You don't hate it. You have no brain.
沒腦子怎麼用？
You've got no brain to exercise.
西牛皮，我在孤兒院時有沒有打過架
Didn't we fight well in orphanage?
那不是打架，叫打你
They were beatings, not fights.
那時候你只會跪地求饒
And you pleading on your knees.
男人的一生只是爭兩樣東西
Man fights for two things.
第一是女人
Woman.
第二…是一口氣
Face.
怎麼樣？打我好了
You dare to touch me?
打你就打你，用不著死的
Big deal! Want to touch me?
我不敢打你嗎？
Who says l can't.
我打還你
Here it comes.
你兩個不要打了，很易受傷的
Stop the fight.
關你什麼事
lt's none of your business.
這場架是打定的，我要打你怎麼樣？
The fight must go on. Here l come.
你別再打我
Don't you dare to do it again!
再打
Come again.
如果我是別人，你早就被人打了
lf l were you, l'd be beaten to death.
我希望你不要再打我
Don't touch me, l warn you.
我要打你，怎麼樣？
l'll do exactly that.
你不要打我行不行？
Can you stop beating me?
我就是要打
l just don't want to stop.
我警告你，你別再打我
Don't hit me, l warn you.
我再打你一下，怎麼樣？
One more hit, and l'll...
你敢再打我一下？
You dare hit me again?
化干戈為玉帛…
Let there be peace.
你為什麼踢我？
Why did you kick me?
是你自己說的在你精神集中的時候
You told me to divert your attention.
分散你的注意力
When you were concentrating.
你沒看見我在救人嗎？
Didn't you see l was rescuing people?
你信不信我望爆你的肚子
Want me watch how you explode.
他…
He...
幸好不是我，望一望都會肚痛
l would have stomach-ache.
我先
l'll go first.
什麼事？
What's the matter?
是你？
So it's you!
我吃了點葡萄，肚瀉到現在
l have a running stomach.
死了…
Too bad...
這房子有多少廁所
Say, how many toilets are there!
一共有五個，不過這個我在用
Five. But l'm using this.
老總，你知不知道
Do you know...
左邊的草長還是右邊的草長？
Which side has longer grass?
你的右邊
lt's on your right.
別再搞了
Don't do it again.
大家好點了嗎？
Are you all ready?
你是誰？    我…
Say, just who are you? l...
他就是那年抓我去的那個沙展
He's the inspector who hauled me in.
以前是，但現在是特警組的總警司
No more inspector. Now senior superintendent.
我姓曹，英文名叫華德
l am Tsao, Walter to you.
鷓鴣菜，你串同警察來陷害我
Kidstuff, you are in league with cops.
這不關我的事，真的
lt's not me.
陷害我們
You frame us.
豈有此理，起來
Damn! Get up!
不要
Don't...
不關他的事，是我逼他的
He's not to blame. l forced him.
那也不關我們的事，我們可以走了
We're not to blame too. Bye!
不要心急
One moment.
開電視機看看有什麼特別報告
See what's the news on TV.
有什麼新聞
What's the news?
我不知道
l don't know.
然後再炒兩下，這個菜就算做好了
Two more turns and it's cooked.
各位觀眾，現在有一項特別新聞報告
Here's a special news bulletin.
今日下午二時六名男女蒙面劫匪
Six masked armed men and women broke into.
闖入尖沙嘴東部嘉禾銀行
Harvest Bank at 2 p.m.
用槍指嚇行內職員
They robbed the bank.
並迅速劫去港幣二千萬元
Of $20,000,000
然後逃去無蹤
and escaped.
以下是本台記者在案發現場的訪問
Our reporter is now at the bank.
到現在為止警方有沒有掌握到線索？
Have the police found any clue?
有的，這六名男女劫匪
Sure.
雖然蒙著面去打劫
We know who they are.
根據可靠的線索
We've got some reliable clues.
我們警方已經知道他們的外號
We can only identify them by nicknames.
是西牛皮
They are Rawhide.
鷓鴣菜、大生地
Kidstuff. Sandy.
羅漢果、花旗參
Roundhead and Herb.
和霸王花    謝謝
And Ba Wah. Thanks.
特別報告完畢
That's the end of the news.
不關我的事
l didn't do it.
不關我的事，你們相信我
l didn't do it.Trust me.
你們不要這麼衝動，這事完全是安排
Don't panic. l arranged it.
你們現在是警方的通緝犯，你逃不了
Now you are under arrest.
不過現在你們這個竇
However only l know your hideout.
只有我一個人知道
l'm the only person who knows.
沒有人知道
Nobody else knows.
你們放心
l can assure you.
這件事除了我之外，沒有人知道
Nobody knows it, except me.
甚至我到這兒來見你們也是秘密行動
And l am here on secret mission.
真的？
Really?
以我華德曹的人格來保證
My word for that.
各位兄弟，我有一個提議
Boys, l have an idea.
既然曹警司單人匹馬到此地來
Since nobody knows he's here.
又神不知鬼不覺
No one knows.
不如玩以前的遊戲
Let's play a game.
是不是五大寇怒打衙差
ls it called 5 to 1.
對
Right.
救命…不要打…
Help! Help!
別動…
Don't move.
別動，把手放在頭上
Don't move. Put your hands on your head.
幸虧我的人格早就賣給了香港政府了
Lucky. l'd sold off my reputation.
不然早就給你們打死了
Or you'd killed me.
只要你們不打我，他們就不會動你們
lf you spare me, police won't touch you.
怎麼樣？
How about that.
不打了…
Don't dare.
好，沒事了，收隊…
lt's all over. Let's go.
是，收隊
Yes Sir. Let's go.
各位是聰明人
You are all clever men.
應該明白你們已經是勢成騎虎的了
You realize the impossible spot you're in.
我不會令你們孤立無援
l won't let you down.
我有一個最得力的助手陪你們一齊去
So l am giving you my best assistant.
不用了，我們五個人就夠了
No need. The 5 of us will do.
說得對
Right.
千萬別叫我們跟皇家警察並肩作戰
Don't ever let me be seen with cops.
免得大家狼狽為奸
People may say we're informers.
我不知道
l don't know.
我們每次合作都是跟警方作對
Police have been against me.
現在要我們跟他合作，很難了
lt's hard for me to help the cops.
我支持你
l'm for you.
美女
Miss.
你找誰？
Who are you looking for?
我是曹警司的助手
l'm the superintendent's assistant.
我叫溫納斯，我幫你拿行李
My name's Venus. Let me have the baggage.
請進來
Come in!
謝謝
Thanks.
曹SIR
Sup. Tsao, Sir.
你來了，不過來也沒有用了
Sorry to see you come in vain.
我們一致認為
We are agreed with your assistant.
有你這麼機警的警務人員幫助我們
We are helped by excellent cops.
這件事已經成功了一半
Well begun half is done.
是的
Yes.
歡迎…
Welcome.
Welcome! Welcome!
我代表大家歡迎你，請過去坐
l welcome you on their behalf.
好
Good.
請坐…
Please sit.
請讓一下
Please don't get in the way.
請坐…
Please sit.
現在我也該回去了
As it is, l've got to go.
至於行動的細節，胡小姐會告訴你們
Miss Woo will tell you the details.
行了    密司胡…
Alright Miss Woo.
你們四個怎麼還不送曹警司出去
You four see him to the door.
不用了，現在還有誰肯走開
Nobody want to step out.
密司胡，你過來
Miss Woo, come over.
請
Please.
你照計劃去做
Do as you are told.
知道
l know.
好了，祝你們成功
Wish all of you luck.
你早點回去吧，再見
Go back and goodbye.
拜拜…
Goodbye!
現在我首先自我介紹，我姓胡
Let me introduce myself. The name's Woo.
隸屬皇家警察特警組第一小隊
First Special Group, Royal HK Police.
職位是督察，你們可以叫我胡督察
You may call me inspector Woo.
不過為了掩飾身份
But as cover up,
大家最好叫我霸王花
call me Ba Wah.
原來她就是霸王花
So she's Ba Wah.
她不講我不知道嗎？
l didn't know until she said it.
霸王花小姐
Miss Ba Wah.
是誰？
Who is that?
什麼事？
What's the matter?
你聽不見有聲音嗎？
Did you hear any noise?
沒有
Nothing.
剛才我看見一個黑影，可能在你房裏
Strange! l saw a shadow in your room.
是不是在你這兒
lsn't it hiding here.
幹什麼你，你的橋段太舊了，出去
Don't playact any more.
好，你保重吧
Okay, take care.
不許動，打劫
Don't move. lt's a holdup.
真的打劫
ls it for real?
別老是看著我，不然一刀要你的命
Don't stare at me. l'll kill you.
大哥，現在怎麼辦？
Now what to do?
不許動…
Don't move.
綁起他們
Tie them up.
起來…
Get up!
不要反抗，他們真的會殺人的
Don't resist; no resistance, they're killer.
把繩子拿過來
Get me the rope.
聰明點的話就別出聲，不然殺了你
Don't make a sound, or l will kill you.
你不用怕，時間很快就過去了
So don't panic. lt'll be over soon.
等安全的時候我們就大聲叫救命
Call for help only when you're safe.
大生地，輪到你進去了，快點
Sandy, your turn. Fast.
快點，進去
Make it snappy.
怎麼會這樣，發生什麼事？
What happened to cause this?
我們被人打劫
We were robbed.
被人打劫？怎麼搞的？
Robbed? How can?
不用怕，我替你解開繩子
Let me untie the ropes.
大生地，你在這兒保護霸王花
Sandy, protect Ba Wah.
我馬上去報警
l'll call police.
霸王花，有我在這裏不用怕
l'm here. Don't be afraid.
別動，我們打劫…
Don't move! Robbed...
打劫…
Robbed...
有我在這裏，你也敢打劫
You dare to rob us with me here?
你們想怎麼樣？
What do you want?
走開
Get away.
大哥，我們現在該怎麼辦？
Now what do l do?
綁起他
Tie up!
別動
Don't move!
綁緊一點
Tie it tighter.
搜查一下
Search for it.
沒什麼東西，散水    是
Nothing. Let go! Alright.
既然是這樣，我們來跳個舞吧
As it is, let's dance.
跳…跳你個頭
As it is, you want to dance?
發生什麼事？
What happened?
沒事…
Nothing! Nothing!
我們讓人打劫了
We were robbed.
打劫
Robbed.
你保護她，我去報警
You protect here while l call police.
還不夠
That's not enough.
你去哪裏？
Where're you going?
進去
Going in there.
進去換衣服
Get changed.
快點進去…
Get in now...
別動，打劫
Hold up.
又打劫了
Another robbery?
你想怎麼樣？
What do you really want?
我們只是劫財不是劫色，過去那邊
We're not after women. Move over.
死胖子，快走到那邊
Fatso, you move over there too.
好重，我不能呼吸了
So heavy, l'm dying.
死胖子，你別亂來了
Fatso, don't you dare!
我知道了
l know that.
沒事了，走吧
Let's go.
別怕
Don't be afraid.
謝謝你
Thanks.
先走吧    就快有人來的
Let's go. People will come soon.
發生什麼事？
What happened?
打劫
We are robbed.
哈哈，打劫嗎？
Robbery once again?
你保護她，我去報警
Protect her. l'll call police.
好…
Alright.
輪到你們了
lt's your turn.
快點…
Hurry up...
你沒事吧？    不許動
Are you all right? Freeze!
不許動…打劫…
Don't move...Hold up...
我暈了
l fainted.
大哥，怎麼樣了？
Big Brother, what now.
綁起她
Tie up.
不要動
Don't move.
到我了…等了那麼久終於輪到我了
lt's finally my turn.
羅漢果，發生什麼事？
What, what happened?
沒什麼，你先出去吧，不要理我
Nothing particular. Nothing.
看你們的樣子，一定是被人打劫了
You look like robbery victims.
真可憐，讓我先把繩子解開，很辛苦
Let me untie you. Let me.
沒事了，不用怕
Don't be afraid.
謝謝你    行了，沒事了
Thank you. lt's alright.
我們一塊兒去報警
You two go together.
神經病，一塊兒去報警誰保護霸王花
Can't do that. Someone's got to protect her.
出去，還不出去
Go right away.
你也是的，被人打劫就應大聲叫喊
Cry for help when robbed.
你早點大聲叫我便早點進來
And l'll come back fast.
你就用不著這麼辛苦了
And you don't have to...
其實我是最關心你的
suffer so much.
不許動，打劫
lt's a holdup.
是…打劫
lt's...robbery.
又打劫了
Another robbery?
是，又打劫
So it's another robbery.
大哥大，是不是把他們紮起來
Big Brother, tie them up together.
不錯，因為我剛來的時候
Right. When l came.
我發覺那個男人太囂張了
That guy's full of conceit.
所以我多拿了一條繩子來
So l planned...
打算把他們分開綁
to tie them up separately.
分開綁？
Tie up separately.
好不好？
ls that all right?
好
Good.
不綁了…
l quit.
剛才你們幾個都綁在一起
They were tied together.
輪到我就分開綁
Why must l singly?
不玩了…
No more game for me.
羅漢果你這個死鬼
Roundhead's to blame.
我早就說你不夠義氣的了
l saw through you.
我不是羅漢果
l'm not Roundhead.
你以為蒙了面就沒人認識你嗎
The hood couldn't hide you identity.
不關我的事，我跟你什麼也沒發生過
lt's really none of my business.
對不起，我們跟你開玩笑的
Sorry, we were having a little fun.
不玩了…
No more for me.
你們全都給滾出去
All of you get out.
出去    拜拜
Get out. Bye.
太離譜了，這有什麼好玩的
What's there left to play?
太晚了，我們去睡吧
lt's very late. Let's sleep.
滾出去
Go out.
歡迎…
Welcome, welcome...
晚了，我們去睡覺吧
lt's late. Go to sleep.
不好意思
l am sorry.
不好意思，我們開玩笑
l'm sorry. We were joking.
我們走吧
Go now.
各位站好
Stand properly.
預備，笑一笑
Ready. Smile.
多拍一張
One more picture.
我們扮成這副樣子
We're dressed so.
是不是真的有架飛機讓我們開
ls there a plane for us?
開就沒得開，打就有你的份兒
No plane. But beatings aplenty.
打？怎麼打
Beatings? What beatings?
問問霸王花好了
Ask Ba Wah.
各位團友，我們可以走了
Everybody, we may go now.
矮子，你該知道怎麼打了
Now you know.
這樣打
Like this.
打我？你這死小鬼
Beating me? You're asking for trouble.
羅漢果，整天只顧開玩笑，我打死你
Naughty Roundhead! l'll kill you.
進去    算了…
Get in. Come on, come on!
你們在這裏等一等，我幫你們登記
Wait here. l'll book a room for you.
你們在這裏站著，我去廁所一趟
Wait here. l'm going to the bathroom.
我也去喝點水
l'll go for some water.
讓我看看有什麼漂亮的小妞
Let me see if there are beauties.
站著，不許走開
Stand pat. Don't leave.
阿芳，等一等，我去拿點東西
A minute, l'll get something.
老兄，怎麼走路不帶眼
Say, you forgot to bring along eyes.
你帶眼就應該避開我
You have eyes; so you yield way.
我的眼睛一直沒有空閒過
My eyes have been busy.
你的色眼有什麼好看
Busy peeping, l'm sure.
這個日本女孩長得不錯
That Japanese girl is quite nice.
你怎麼知道她是日本人？
How'd you know she's Japanese.
西洋菜跟紅蘿蔔你分不分得出來
Easy, just like white radish vs. red carried.
羅漢果，蹲在這裏找什麼？拉屎
Roundhead, what are you looking for.
我剛在外邊掉了一百元日幣
l lost $100 outside.
你在門口掉的怎會在這裏找？真笨
But you didn't lose it here.
外面很黑而這裏多亮，當然在這裏找
But here's much brighter for a search.
找…找到天亮，笨蛋
Search, search till it's daylight.
外邊掉了東西這裏怎能找到？
You can't find it here.
找到了，一百元變了五百元
Eureka! Lost $100; found $500.
五百元是我的，你拾什麼？
That's mine; yours is outside.
我們上去吧
Let's go up.
再找找看
Let's search for it.
這裏的環境真不錯
Good place.
你們猜猜誰住這房間
Guess who lives here.
總之不是你
Won't be you though.
我早就有準備了
l do have this in mind.
你們每人都有份，因為這酒店客滿了
You all live here. Hotels are full.
連我也要住在這裏
l'll live here too.
飽了
Wonderful!
那我們豈不是要睡在一起
Now we live altogether.
你們喜歡睡在一起我不反對
l don't mind your living together.
因為你們睡客廳而我睡臥室
You share the living room, bedroom's mine.
我幫你拿好了
Let me help!
霸王花，原來這臥室有兩張床的
Ba Wah, there are too bed.
怎麼樣？    無謂浪費
So what? Don't waste.
對…
Right.
好，你們其中一人睡這張床
All right, one of you get the bed.
你們別失禮人的，出去…
Try to be proper. Out! Out!
霸王花，對不起
Not that,
我們兄弟間有點事要商量，很快就完
let's talk it over.
出去…
Get out.
好了，各位一齊長大的好兄弟
Now, we grow up like brothers.
我西牛皮人到中年
l am older,
青春有限時日無多
not many chances left.
你們當可憐我也好，捱義氣也好
Be charitable and take pity.
讓張床給我好不好？
Let me sleep in t hat bed.
羅漢果，你做個好榜樣，你先講
Roundhead, you speak first.
不行
No.
什麼話？
What's that?
廣東話，人家都說不行了
That's Cantonese lingo for no.
羅漢果，你再講一次
Roundhead, dare you repeat it?
不行…從小到大有那樣不是我讓你？
No, no, l've yielded to you too long.
我長大了我也要結婚的
l'm old enough to get a woman.
追求女孩子我怎能讓你
Can't let you do it first.
好，那就用我們以前解決問題的辦法
Let's use our old way to decide.
好的
Okay.
那天我從你的門前過
l passed your house.
你就拿著水桶往外潑
As you poured water outside.
潑在我的皮鞋上
My shoes caught the water.
路上的行人笑呀笑哈哈
All around there was laughter.
你什麼話也都沒有對我說
You said nothing to me.
你只是瞇著眼睛望著我
You looked at me with half-shut eyes.
Loola!Loola…
Loola! Loola! Loola!
Loola!Loola!
Loola! Loola!
Loola!Loola…
Loola! Loola! Loola!
那一段好笑？
Which part is funny?
我笑你不懂日文在硬充懂的樣子
You're funny trying to look like knowing Japanese.
你識嗎？
And you can?
不行了，我忍無可忍了，我要強姦她
l can't bear it. l must rape her.
等一等
Wait a while.
你真不是人，這時候還講強姦二字
You're a beast, speaking about rape.
不講強姦講什麼？
Then what's the word to use?
輪姦
Gang rape.
好，夠兄弟
Boys, have guts.
進去
Let's go.
那怎麼行？
How could that be?
關你什麼事
None of your business.
走開    別擋著路
Get away. Don't block the way.
霸王花，他們要強姦你
Ba Wah, they want to rape you.
你這個人，霸王花你也想強姦
You want to rape too?
你真的沒人性了
You're worse than a dog.
這種壞主意虧你也想得出來
Coming up with such ideas.
我後悔認識了你
l regret knowing you.
你太下流了
You're rotten.
不好意思踢錯了你
Sorry l kicked you.
不過誤會總是有的，你別怪我
Misunderstandings come and go.
我不會怪你
l don't blame you.
不過不知為什麼這兒痛得很厲害
But it hurts.
閉上你的眼睛
Close you eyes.
那不是看不見了你嗎？
Then l won't see you.
等會兒搽完後不是可以看見我了嗎
You can open your eyes after medication.
我…
l...
不許講話
Don't talk.
搽…撒嬌
Do it...Making a scene out of a nick.
睡在地上，睡在床上太舒服了
Come down; don't stay up.
這張床兩層的，給我一層好嗎？
lt's double deck; let's me have one deck.
你不會搬
You can do the removals yourself.
你認不認識他？
Do you know him?
雞骨草
Skinny Monkey.
對，他到日本就改名叫鐵力威
Right but in Japan he calls himself Muscles.
鷓鴣菜，你…
Kidstuff, you...
你不用多講，我決定不幹了
Nothing doing. l'm quitting.
雞骨草此人從來沒有好的帶挈
Muscles does nothing well.
跟他一起一定死的
One's doomed to be with him.
鷓鴣菜，你不要因私事而耽誤公事
Kidstuff, don't be swayed by your bias.
我不是有意推卸責任
l'm not evading.
而是事實上很難跟他合作
l don't like him.
小時候我跟他一塊兒偷蕃薯
He and l went out stealing, when young.
被人抓到的時候他就說我指使他
And he let me get all the blame.
長大以後我幫他跟人賭十三張
We grew up...
我把好牌全派給他
and set up a card game.
他贏了就一毛錢也不分給我
He won but he won't give me a cent.
我出來做事以後
Then l told him my plan...
我告訴他我預算打劫地下賭場
to rob a casino.
他聽了全盤計劃之後
After he heard the details.
他告訴我他是警察，還帶人去捉賭
He identified himself as cop and nabbed me.
現在你找我跟他合作？
ls he the kind to cooperate?
鷓鴣菜，你望著我
Kidstuff, look at me.
人家說眼睛是靈魂之窗
Eyes speak volumes of words.
若是真的話，你看不看見我的內心？
l'm sure you can read my mind.
我不是很清楚
l don't see anything clearly.
那你靠近一點
Closer.
現在呢？
Now...
我只是看見我自己
l saw my own image.
他就是我內心所有的東西
He's what's in my mind.
你是我眼中的英雄
You are my hero.
但可惜我從來沒你做過一件
But l've done...
轟轟烈烈的事
nothing heroic.
就快有了
lt's coming soon.
這太令人興奮了
lt's so exciting.
我可以親眼看到一個男子漢
l shall see a man
表現出他的英勇果敢
showing his worth.
不屈不撓的永恆的鷓鴣菜
The eternal Kidstuff.
我在這裏…
l'm here...
別阻住我的嘴巴，我用說話來稱讚你
Don't stop my mouth. l'm praising you.
你要照舊勇往直前
Kidstuff, you must be brave.
我們攜手合作把惡勢力消滅，好嗎？
Let's cooperate and wipe them out.
那麼走吧
Let's go.
過分勇猛了
Too brave to be good.
這兒
This place.
鐵力威…
Muscles...
小胖，你別動
Fatso, don't move.
你到這兒來幹什麼？
Why are you here?
相親
Looking for a bride.
鐵力威在哪裏？
Where's that interpol?
我正在找他
l'm looking for him too.
一個都不能放走
Can't let any of them get away.
只有我們兩個人
Only two of us?
還有我
Count me in.
有你在絕對沒有好處
You won't be a help.
就是這個死免崽子了
That's the one.
把他們給殺了
Killed by them.
送給你
For you.
鷓鴣菜，很久沒見了，你好嗎？
Kidstuff, long time no see. How're you?
本來還不錯，不過現在開始就不好了
Good until now l see you.
謝謝你來幫忙
Thank for coming to help.
不用謝了，早知道是你…
l won't if l had known it's you.
小時候的事，暫時不要提
Let's bygones by bygones.
這次我們有重要的任務
We have an important mission.
先把他們綁起來
Bind them up first.
這兒有二千萬日幣，拿去用吧
Here's 20 million, take it.
你會這麼大方嗎？我不要
You're so kind? No, thanks.
這是魚餌來的
This is bait.
謝謝
Thank you.
怎麼樣？有沒有找到那對姦夫淫婦？
So you haven't found the lovers.
我連廁所也找過了，也沒有看見他們
Can't even find them in the toilet.
鷓鴣菜向來是重色輕友，叫東西吃
Kidstuff is not a friend. Order any way.
你好
Hello.
牛奶，火腿煎蛋
Milk, ham and eggs.
他不知你說什麼
He doesn't know what you are talking.
對
Right.
牛奶OK
Milk, okay.
火腿，腿，火腿…
Ham, H-h-ham, Ham, Ham.
煎蛋
Fired eggs.
我？咖啡
Me? Coffee.
咖啡
Coffee,
肉醬意粉
Spaghetti.
肉
Spa...
肉醬…意粉
Spa...ghet...ti.
肉醬意粉
Spaghetti.
公司三文治
Club Sandwich.
英文是…
Club sandwich in English.
即是…公司…三文治
Club sandwich.
麵包…牛油
Bread...Butter.
雞…火腿
Chicken...ham.
麵包…牛油
Bread...Butter.
雞…雞蛋
Chicken...ham.
生菜…番茄，其他不會做了
Lettuce...tomato, that's all l can.
再多個麵包
Glue them together
這麼多層難道不是公司三文治
and we get club sandwich.
明白了沒有？
Understand?
我要…
My order now.
羅漢果，不會叫的就沒得吃
Roundhead, you must learn how to order.
還有，不許叫我們叫過的東西
You must not order what we ate.
西柚汁
Citrus juice.
西柚汁？
Citrus juice?
西柚…汁
C-c-cit-rus juice.
再加一條腸仔
And a sausage.
腸仔？
Sausage?
你怎麼做？
What did you say?
OK
腸仔的日本話你會講？
You can say sausage in Japanese?
我沒跟他講，我只是給他看
l didn't say, l showed him.
很好，公司三文治
Good, club sandwiches.
這裏一帶地下賭場的幕後老闆
The casino's
就是稻草人俱樂部主持人
run by the Scarecrow Club.
所以你們下注的時候不妨大上大落
Make your bets as big as possible.
做成豪華闊綽的給他們看
Just to convince them.
記住，我不會及時出來幫你們
l'll help you out when you need it.
一切隨機應變
Be alert and flexible.
請進
Please come in.
你想賭什麼，隨便好了
Bet on anything you fancy.
你們還不獨沽一味，不是單就是雙
Why! You have only Odd and Even.
沒什麼可以選擇的
Any other choice?
有什麼事情找我好了
Look me up for help.
行了…
Okay...
謝謝…
Thank you...
請坐
Sit down, please.
多贏一點
Good luck!
西牛皮、花旗參
Sandy, Herb,
鷓鴣菜、大生地、羅漢果
Kidstuff, Rawhide, Roundhead.
你們會不會玩？
You know how to play.
霸王花，別提著這些名字，多難聽
Ba Wah, don't use my nickname.
是的
Right.
有個小洞
Look, there's a hole!
看看是幾點？
What's the number you see?
二、三點，單
2,3 - odd number.
你真笨，這麼容易看見還有誰開賭場
They wouldn't be so foolish.
小意思…
lt's nothing, nothing.
沒錯了吧
lt's right, right?
快下注，別把錢放在袋裏
Get out your money and bet.
想帶回香港？
You can't take it back with you.
這次買什麼？
What should we play now.
我怕你不相信，又是單
Play for old number again.
我相信
l believe you.
買
Why didn't you bet?
小姐，不要走
Don't go;
大不了把贏回來的錢還給你
l'll return your loss to you.
反正這些錢都是銀行的
Anyway, it's the bank's money.
這時候還妞什麼呢？
Flirting at this hour!
這些錢帶回去你在香港開個農場都夠
Enough to open up a Hong Kong brothel.
大哥
Hey, Chief?
現在外面來了六個香港人
We get six Hong Kong customers.
聽他們的名字和看他們的樣子
They look like, their names sound like.
好像是早些時候
The six...
在香港打劫銀行那些劫匪一樣
Hong Kong bank robbers.
現在我該怎麼做才對
What should we do?
警察來了…
The cops are here.
香港來的請到這邊來
Please come here, Hong Kong friends.
那邊…
That way.
快走兩步
Hurry up.
謝謝…
Thanks...
來，各位乾杯
Here's my respect.
各位在香港做的事，真令我佩服
You did beautifully in Hong Kong.
的確是後生可畏
My admiration.
我們稻草人俱樂部
Our Scarecrows Club...
很需要你們這些年輕有為的新會員
wants to be friends.
今天大家賞面，盡情享受
Please have a good time.
多看一支舞吧
Stay for another show!
不用了
No need.
對，我現在才知道
Now l realize.
原來日本的伎藝館等如香港的歌廳
Geisha house is like Hong Kong cabaret.
是，我還以為可以陪飲，陪酒
l have the same...
陪笑，陪沖涼，陪…
wrong ideas.
你這傻瓜，這裏不是香港
But this is not Hong Kong.
隨便你說什麼都沒用，不如心如止水
You are too cool to be excited.
我明白各位的意思
l see what you mean.
漂亮的妞我早就為各位準備好
The beautiful girls are prepared.
還過得去
Not bad.
很漂亮
Very beautiful.
松木先生，他們五個喝杯酒
All they need...
吃點東西就行了
is a little food.
因為他們每人都有了追求的理想對像
They all have chosen their girls.
我想他們都不想讓他們的女朋友知道
So they don't want the girls.
他們在外面風花雪月的事，知道嗎？
To know they're fooling around.
既然是這樣，我就不勉強了
lt's your decision.
慢著
Just a minute.
既來之則安之，其實是逢場作戲了
When in Rome, do as the Romans do.
就算是女朋友知道她會原諒我們的
Our girls will understand.
對，所謂人在江湖身不由己
Right, you must think of her.
總之身邊摟著女人但心中仍想著她
Even when you're holding another girl.
是，自古名士多風流
Our history is a romantic one.
我們不會令小妞們失望
We shouldn't disappoint the ladies.
我剛剛失戀，我需要找人陪
l'm out of love; l need consolation.
說，你喜歡怎麼樣就怎麼好了
Say it; whatever you say.
有緣無慾，很難持續的
Platonic love doesn't last.
大家盡情享受，我失陪了
Have a good time. Excuse me.
過來，過來這裏…
Come over here.
怎麼樣？
What's the lowdown?
那五個我不認識，不過我可以肯定
l don't know five of the men.
當我做警察的時候
But Fatso used to...
小胖是跟鐵力威在一起
be with interpol.
你放心
Don't worry.
羅漢果，換個位置
Roundhead, change seat.
為什麼？
Why?
我一向跟你講話要解釋的嗎？過來
l don't have to give a reason.
起來
Get up.
我看你們其中一位
l hope one of you...
暫時要離開這個溫柔鄉
leave this place.
我希望你們盡快成為我們的會員
And become member of our club.
所以要先盡會員的義務
Club members have functions to carry out.
你們誰人回去拿錢來？
Who will go back to fetch the money?
這重要任務我自問太大意擔當不起
l don't think l'm qualified.
我一向輕佻浮躁，也不適合
Me either. l'm too frivolous.
我神經有點問題，隨時會發作的
My nerves. They act up any time.
各位大哥，我想你們不會把重要任務
l'm sure you won't trust this task.
交給一個低能的兒童
To a retarded child.
好了…讓我去，反正那些錢是我收藏
Fine, l'll go and get the money.
馬朝    是
Mah. Yes.
送這位先生回去
See this gentleman out.
知道
Yes, Sir.
霸王花，你要自己照顧自己了
Ba Wah, you have to care for yourself.
什麼時候我都是自己照顧自己
l've been doing exactly that.
走吧，鷓鴣菜，別自作多情了
Go, Kidstuff. Don't ham it up.
快點，少只電爐少隻鬼
Quick, cut it short.
香爐
You used the wrong expression.
香爐就香爐，回去再告訴我不行嗎？
Okay, tell me later please.
你們慢慢享受吧
Enjoy yourself!
鷓鴣菜…
Kidstuff...
自己替自己解決吧
Your own problem.
鐵力威，三四一六一七
Telephone, 341617.
鷓鴣菜？
Kidstuff.
你是誰？
Who are you?
我是鐵力威，現在情形怎麼樣？
l'm Muscles. How's everything?
他們五個人留在那邊
They are all left behind.
我回來拿兩千萬去贖人
l'm to ransom them out with $20 million.
不是贖人，是深入虎穴
Ransom nothing. lt's war.
什麼都不成問題，現在怎麼辦？
Same to me. How do we proceed?
我去拿給你
l'll get it for you.
快點，我等你
Okay, l'll wait here.
你還有心情去玩
You have the heart to play?
我怎麼知道進來的是不是你
How could l know it's you.
原來二千萬是這麼多的
$20 million could be so little.
這裏是一千萬不是二千萬
That's not $20 million.
講明是二千萬
We said $20 million.
你給一千萬，什麼意思？
Why did you take half away?
人家只要一半，你幹麼全拿去
They demanded only half of it.
他們約了你在什麼地方交錢
Where should you meet them?
他叫我明天在遊樂場
Tomorrow;
自然會有人跟我聯絡
at the carnival.
我也知道在遊樂場
That l know.
可是不知在哪個地方
But which part of carnival.
這樣吧，這裏有一個火機
Take this lighter.
當你打著火，我就收到信號了
One flick and we get the signal.
記住，一踏進虎穴就馬上告訴我
Remember to flick as soon as possible.
試試看
Try it.
鷓鴣菜
Kidstuff.
別不分皂白的亂打，醒定一點
Don't throw wild punches.
不用東張西望了，我是鐵力威
Don't look any further. l'm your man.
你嚇不到我的
You can't scare me.
這裏有那麼多燈籠
There are so many lanterns here.
有大，也有圓的
There're big ones and round ones.
嚇死我了
Scared me to death.
假的
lt's fake.
有膽子就放馬過來
Come on if you've got the guts.
來真的
Let's do it seriously.
把它脫下來再跟你們玩
Take it off before playing with you.
我的朋友呢？
Where's my friend?
你們在香港搶銀行的事及你拿來的錢
The bank robbery you committed and the money you brought.
我們已查過了
We have investigated the case.
不用告訴我結果
Don't tell me the result.
兩樣都是假的
Both are not true.
這些東西我們也有賣的
We sell this too.
大陸仔    有
Mainlander. Yes.
拿著打火機走上富士山頂
Take the lighter and walk up the Fuji Mountain.
一路走抽多點煙，打多幾次火
Smoke as you walk, light up more.
帶多幾盒火柴，沒有多少瓦斯了
Bring some matches. There's not much gas left.
是嗎？
Yes?
真是人頭豬腦
Stupid.
一打火不是告訴警察我們總部在這裏
The police will know where out headquarters is by the light.
出去，去到山頂
Go, go to the peak.
若給警察追到就自己跳下火山口
lf the cops get you, then jump down the volcano.
這輩子別回來了    知道
Don't ever come back. l get it.
帶他進去鎖住他    是
Lock him up. Yes.
收拾好東西    是
Pack your stuff. Yes.
走
Go.
你現在才進來
You come in now.
對，我們剛才在這不知多好玩
Yes, we're having a good time.
拿著
Take it.
還有一個密探在哪裏
Where is the spy?
再不說打昏你
l'll beat you up if you don't tell me.
不是我厲害是他差勁而已
l'm not good. lt's just that he's weak.
鐵力威，你厲害
Muscles, you are great.
暈倒…
Pass out...
別打我…都說別打我
Don't hit me. l said don't hit me.
大哥，看著我    鎮定點
Look at me. Calm down.
沒事的，有我在，定打不到你
Don't worry, l'm here. You'll be fine.
你怎麼了
Are you alright?
能幹，先起來…你沒事吧
Get up...are you okay?
沒事，你呢？    沒事
l'm fine. You? Alright.
你這王八蛋找女人哄我們來這兒
You asked us to come here.
找我們來喂蚊子
Now we're feeding the mosquitoes.
我們決定打他    打他
We decide to beat him up. Beat him.
打他…上
Go get him.
真勇敢    還差多少
Save him. ls it okay?
差一點    追
Almost. Let's go.
力奇    開了才說
Ricky. Let's do it first.
我會擺平她的
l'll take care of her.
她真是很厲害
She is good.
你只是打工的，何必這麼拚命
You're just an employee. Don't work too hard.
我拚命是為了想升職，不行嗎
l want to get promoted, isn't that good?
我輸了
l lose.
那邊…
That way...
上邊有很多警察…我們快走
There are many cops. Let's go.
怕什麼，我們也是警察
Don't worry. We are cops too.
對的    是…
Right. Yes...
鷓鴣菜，這次謝謝你們了
Kidstuff, thanks for everything.
不用多謝，我們以不想再見到你
We don't want to see you again.
找部車子送你們好了
Find a paddy wagon for them.
不要，我們五個不想再坐警車
No paddy wagon for us, please.
人長大了，要生性一點，知道嗎
Grow up.
那天你從我們的門前過
l passed your house.
你將水桶往外潑
As you poured water outside.
潑在我的皮鞋上
My shoes caught the water.
路上的行人笑哈哈
All around there was a laughter.
你什麼話也沒有對我說
You said nothing to me.
你只是瞇著眼睛望著我
You looked at me with half-shut-eyes.
Loola!Loola!Loola!
Loola! Loola! Loola!
Loola!Loola!Loola!Hey!Hey!
Loola! Loola! Loola! Hey! Hey!